KARTIK SHAH

kartik.isworking@gmail.com | +61 404 874 569

https://ikartiks.github.io/ | https://github.com/ikartiks | https://in.linkedin.com/in/ikartiks

Summary of Experience

I have 7.3 years of experience in various domains like Banking, digital marketing & healthcare. My core forte is Android, but I have worked on both frontend and backend using technologies like Angular JS, Spring & Hibernate. I have also worked on NoSql technologies like CouchDb which offers in built sync mechanism with conflict resolution. I provide end to end Omni channel experience to clients as per requirements. I like building products. Love to teach & learn. Looking for an opportunity at Sydney, New South Wales, Australia (State sponsored PR holder).

Android experience 7+ years
JavaScript frameworks 3 years
Backend using Spring JPA & Hibernate or core PHP 2-3 years
Experience with Couch DB 1 year

Education

Bachelor of Engineering, Information Technology, Mumbai University, 2011

Certifications

Google & Udacity's Android Developer Nanodegree Udacity's Self Driving Car Nanodegree (Ongoing)

Technical Skills

Strong: Android, Kotlin, BackBase, CouchDB, Building voice actions with Home

Knowledgeable: Angular JS, Spring, JPA, Hibernate, HTML, CSS, SQL, Oracle, Python, Machine Learning, core PHP, RXJava /RXKotlin,

observables

Methodology: Agile using Jira & Pivotal Tracker, SCRUM, Kanban boards.

Tools: Jenkins for Continues integration, Burp Suite for network security, J-meter for load testing, GIT for version control.

Work Experience

Apr 2019 - Present, Frollo Sydney, Australia

- I work on an app for Volt bank, build on top of the Frollo SDK, so my major chunk of work here includes having an aesthetic UI.
- The app allows you to link your bank account, view your transactions, expenses set savings goals.
- I mainly work on the frontend of this application, although I have worked parts of the frollo SDK and app as well.

Jan 2019 – April 2019, Telstra via Luvo (contract). Sydney, Australia

• Working on Telstra's 24x7 app. I worked mainly on their messaging module, as well as redesigning some of the app modules.

Indian Experience

OCT 2015 – OCT 2018, Tata Consultancy Services. IT Analyst, Mumbai

HDFC Bank

Responsibilities

- Leading a team of 7 developers to build a Banking application (HDFC). App has 10M+ installs & 3.9 * rating.
- Build on top of Backbase native hybrid framework to provide logistic navigation from page A to page B.
- To provide native components and compatibility for bridging gap of native and hybrid application.
- To make app secure using reverse engineering tools and SSL Pinning.
- To collaborate with frontend, backend and 3rd party teams for optimal solutions to different banking requirements.
- To collaborate with stake holders from the bank for feature request to providing implementation solutions that best fit the banks needs as well as customer satisfaction.
- To guide both the Android & IOS teams regarding the solution implementation & best practices.
- End to end delivery for Android is my responsibility. Both teams are eventually led by Solutions architect.
- Optimization of apps for faster page rendering and 0 lag time.
- Building new native components and optimizing existing ones provided by Backbase to meet Bank's requirement.

Environment

Google play console, Android Studio, Jenkins, Burp Suite, J-meter, Jira, GIT

Sony Pictures Entertainment

Responsibilities

- Built a hybrid app using PhoneGap for Sony Picture Entertainment's Digital windows project.
- I looked into the JavaScript part of the same using Angular JS V1.5.x.
- Built, developed websites (backend and frontend) and native mobile application for Sony Picture Entertainment's SmartR project, SOAR.
- I handled the support work for backend development as well as frontend development for minor requirement changes to existing project.

Environment Eclipse, JBoss, Jenkins, Pivotal Tracker

Responsibilities

- Led & performed development & maintenance using server side using Spring, JPA, and Hibernate for EPM Ware project.
- Managed complete lifecycle of mobile app Vee Smart Home (VSH).
- Created services in PHP for consumption in mobile app.
- Entire design, development was done by me alone.
- I was the sole android developer in the company back then.

Environment Eclipse, GIT, Android Studio

Mar 2014 - Nov 2014, Gray Matrix Developer, Mumbai

Responsibilities

Team Tracker

- Led the development of this project.
- Handling a team of 2 other Android developers and 3 iOS developers
- Team Tracker was a product that helped us gain many customers as company's first product.
- It was built upon CouchDB, a NoSql database which offered in built document sync and conflict resolution
- The app is a messaging and location tracking app for a corporate organization.

Cakesnapp & Dr. Fixit

- Cakesnapp was a PhoneGap based hybrid application where as Dr Fixit was native hybrid.
- Handling a team of 2 other Android developers and 3 iOS developers
- Communicating with stakeholders for requirement gathering and implementation
- Collaborating with design teams to get the designs right for both the platforms.
- Cakesnapp was a professional contact sharing app.
- I was also a part of the frontend team to write JavaScript for both the platforms.

Environment Eclipse, PHP, PhoneGap GIT.

May 2013 - Mar 2014, Megasys India Developer, Mumbai

Responsibilities

- Built, developed & designed complete lifecycle of 'IMSafe' mobile app, which was appreciated across states and within the
 media as well.
- This is a women safety app, and with the collaboration of regional police to show alerts.
- I managed end to end lifecycle of the app and was the sole developer for this project.
- One of the links for its appreciation in media https://youtu.be/KzXYsg1rzrs
- I was the sole android developer in the company back then.

Environment Eclipse.

Feb 2012 - May 2013, Experience Commerce Pvt. Ltd. Developer, Mumbai

Responsibilities

- This is a digital marketing firm, and most apps made during the time were end customer based with the focus of customer acquisition. All the applications mentioned below except DNA, had the same core concept There is a campaign, and based on client specific needs, user has to add a photo and earn rewards for it. He may earn additional points for sharing the same on social media. At the end of the campaign users with most points are rewarded.
- Few exceptions included developing an app for USL which was store specific and hence never delivered to playstore. It was more of a display app to see the various offerings by USL.
- Built & developed apps for engaging brands like Britannia, Castrol cricket, IPL Team Royal Challengers Bangalore, United Spirits Limited, Adlabs Imagica and Daily News Analysis (DNA) newspaper.
- I have also written some of the PHP & frontend scripts for mobile in projects like iHealthU and CastrolCricket.
- I was the sole android developer back then.

Environment Eclipse, PHP

Major Projects

Frollo	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=us.frollo.frollo.prod	Kotlin, LiveData, TDD
Telstra 24x7	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.telstra.mobile.android.mytelstra	Kotlin, RxJava / RxKotlin, TDD
HDFC Bank GRE Flashcards & Tests (My product)	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.snapwork.hdfc https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.kartik.grevocab	Android, Backbase, Kotlin Android, Kotlin
YRD Health app	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.yrdtechnologies (in beta, request access)	Android, Kotlin

Spring, Hibernate JPA, SPE - SmartR, Digital Windows AngularJS, Phonegap **EPMWare** http://epmware.com/ Home Automation Android, PHP app Dr. Fixit https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pidilite.drfixit Hybrid app development https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.graymatrix.teamtracker Team Tracker Android, Couch database ImSafe Android USL's RCB IPL Team $\underline{https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.royalchallengers.android}$ Android, core JS, PHP USL's Signature $\underline{https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.usl.signatureselfies}$ Android, core JS, PHP Selfies app Britania's iHealthU https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ihealthu.program.challenge Android, core JS, PHP Adlabs Imagica https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.adlabs.themepark Android, core JS, PHP **Castrol Cricket** https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.castrolcricket.android Android, core JS, PHP $\underline{https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.experiencecommerce.android}$ EC Diwali cracker Android, core JS, PHP app

Awards & Leadership

- Best team award at TCS, Client appreciation across multiple projects.
- Complete sponsorship to Mobile developer summit held in Bangalore 2013.
- Complete sponsorship to Udacity & Google's Android Developer Nanodegree course.
- Complete sponsorship to Google's Android Career summit Bangalore 2016 for top 50 selected Android developers across India.
- Conducted multiple trainings in JAVA, Android & JavaScript at TCS, single training on Machine Learning.